<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.ankiweb.Anki</id>
  <translation type="gettext">anki</translation>
  <name>Anki</name>
  <summary>Powerful, intelligent flash cards</summary>
  <developer_name>Damien Elmes</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>Anki is a program which makes remembering things easy. Because it's a lot more efficient than traditional study methods, you can either greatly decrease your time spent studying, or greatly increase the amount you learn.</p>
    <p>Anyone who needs to remember things in their daily life can benefit from Anki. Since it is content-agnostic and supports images, audio, videos and scientific markup (via LaTeX), the possibilities are endless.</p>
  </description>
  <kudos>
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
    <kudo>UserDocs</kudo>
  </kudos>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <url type="homepage">https://apps.ankiweb.net/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://anki.tenderapp.com/discussions/ankidesktop</url>
  <url type="help">https://apps.ankiweb.net/docs/manual.html</url>
  <url type="donation">https://apps.ankiweb.net/support/</url>
  <url type="translate">https://apps.ankiweb.net/docs/manual.html#_app_translations</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image type="source">https://i.imgur.com/zauNqLH.png</image>
      <caption>Flashcard and answer</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release date="2020-08-23" version="2.1.31">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Show card counts in pie graph, and other minor graph tweaks.</li>
          <li>Fix sync error+lost review when undoing in v2 filtered deck with scheduling off.</li>
          <li>Fix crash when dragging &amp; dropping, thanks to ANH25.</li>
          <li>Fix ‘stale notetype’ error after sync+add.</li>
          <li>Close “edit current” when current card deleted.</li>
          <li>Code improvements thanks to ANH, Arthur, Evandro, Henrik and Thomas.</li>
          <li>Find&amp;Replace completion is now case sensitive.</li>
          <li>Fix crash when recovering notes with missing notetype.</li>
          <li>Fix duplicate detection when input text is not normalized.</li>
          <li>Fix Empty Cards not ignoring BR tags.</li>
          <li>Fix Find&amp;Replace window sizing.</li>
          <li>Fix handling of nested legacy template directives.</li>
          <li>Fix issues with bulk tag removal.</li>
          <li>Fix mpv failing to play audio after it’s restarted, thanks to Kelciour.</li>
          <li>Fix some (rare) crashes.</li>
          <li>Full syncs and media syncs now terminate more quickly when the connection breaks.</li>
          <li>Improve support for getting proxies from Windows registry.</li>
          <li>Remove embedded direction markers in RTL cloze deletions.</li>
          <li>Strip nul characters from tags.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-08-09" version="2.1.30">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix move into/out of filtered decks not syncing.</li>
          <li>Add right axis to graphs.</li>
          <li>Add night mode and mobile class toggles in card layout screen (thanks to ANH25).</li>
          <li>Card counts graph now always shows table.</li>
          <li>Catch negative review times in DB check.</li>
          <li>Code improvements (thanks to Matt, phwoo, Evandro and aplaice).</li>
          <li>Fix a crash in the DB check when a note type was missing.</li>
          <li>Fix automatic logout not working when auth failure occurs.</li>
          <li>Fix deck list and graphs not including v2 scheduler cards with rescheduling disabled.</li>
          <li>Fix early reviews not appearing in review graph.</li>
          <li>Fix hour graph problem in timezones west of UTC.</li>
          <li>Fix negated conditonals being non-negated when renamed.</li>
          <li>Fix some syncing errors that could happen until Check Database was run.</li>
          <li>Fix some young cards being shown as mature in reviews graph.</li>
          <li>Handle multiple same-numbered clozes in cloze-only filter.</li>
          <li>Refresh tag list after clearing empty tags.</li>
          <li>Other minor fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-08-22" version="2.1.15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>The V2 scheduler now fully randomizes review cards due on a given day.</li>
          <li>Fix add-ons errors on Windows when profile path was short.</li>
          <li>Fix flag changes in Browse screen not syncing.</li>
          <li>Cleanup recording wav file when recording canceled.</li>
          <li>Fix the window icon on Wayland (thanks to Wilco).</li>
          <li>Add a progress bar to media deletion.</li>
          <li>Other minor changes.</li>
          <li>Fix a bug in the V2 scheduler that would cause partially learnt cards removed from filtered decks to revert to an earlier state.</li>
          <li>Fix a bug in the handling of relearning cards when switching back to the V1 scheduler.</li>
          <li>Fix lost space when pasting indented text.</li>
          <li>Limit image height relative to window height, not document height.</li>
          <li>Fix deck list being re-rendered unnecessarily.</li>
          <li>Remove the unable to connect to local port message.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-05-20" version="2.1.13">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix some issues that cause the main window to get stuck</li>
          <li>Fix an empty deck list sometimes appearing when restoring from a backup</li>
          <li>Fix Anki hanging after an error occurs during startup</li>
          <li>Fix error message when syncing with an unconfirmed email address</li>
          <li>Use jsonschema for add-on manifests (thanks to Erez)</li>
          <li>Warn in DB check when high due numbers are encountered</li>
          <li>Improve error messages on full disk and failed add-on deletion</li>
          <li>Fix relearning cards being given learning step count in V2 scheduler</li>
          <li>Fix preview window failing to appear when show both sides enabled</li>
          <li>Removing trailing BR tag when pasting into an empty field</li>
          <li>Don’t throw an error when non-Latin text in the Javascript console can’t be shown</li>
          <li>Double click on add-ons to edit their configuration (thanks to lovac42)</li>
          <li>Fix the window icon in a few screens (thanks to John)</li>
          <li>Improve the default type in the answer note type</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-04-23" version="2.1.12">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix fields appearing under editor buttons</li>
          <li>Fix memory leak in card layout screen</li>
          <li>Fix some issues with previewing in the Browse screen</li>
          <li>Fix card counts not updating when a review is undone</li>
          <li>Fix an error caused by missing note types</li>
          <li>Fix an issue checking for add-on updates (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Disable add-on config button when not appropriate (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Tweaks to the deck age graph binning (thanks to Jian)</li>
          <li>Add-ons hosted on AnkiWeb can now define conflicts in the manifest file</li>
          <li>Make sure mpv doesn’t attempt to load scripts from default location</li>
          <li>Other minor fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-03-11" version="2.1.11">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Change Undo shortcut back to Ctrl+Alt+Z/Cmd+Opt+Z in Browse screen, to prevent accidentally undoing non-text changes when editing fields</li>
          <li>Revert a previous card template optimization that could cause an error</li>
          <li>Suppress a spurious error message that could occur when editing</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-03-07" version="2.1.10">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add option to strip html in export</li>
          <li>Avoid nbsp for single spaces when pasting text</li>
          <li>Fix preview screen flashing when moving between cards</li>
          <li>Improvements to the add-ons screen (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Support .ankiaddon bundles (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Improve subpixel antialiasing on some machines (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Fix inability to start if problem occurs on first run</li>
          <li>Allow decreasing daily limits in custom study</li>
          <li>Add a button to copy debug info to about screen (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Allow add-ons to serve files from mediasrv (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>More user-friendly error messages for some network errors</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-02-20" version="2.1.9">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Update standard build to latest toolkit version</li>
          <li>Hardware acceleration defaults to off again on Windows/Linux, due to the issues it was causing some users. If you were not experiencing any issues, turning hardware acceleration back on in the preferences screen is recommended</li>
          <li>Various statistics fixes for the V2 scheduler, including an automatic remapping of button 2/3 in the review history when moving back and forth between scheduler versions so the "answer buttons" graph displays correctly</li>
          <li>Fix BR tags being included in empty fields (thanks to David and zjosua)</li>
          <li>Optimize card template repositioning (thanks to Arthur)</li>
          <li>Fix a crash when copying/cutting with an empty selection (thanks to David)</li>
          <li>Avoid screen flash when undoing reviews</li>
          <li>Make sure info/warning dialogs appear on top</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with just-typed text not being saved when using the mouse to save/add a card</li>
          <li>Added support for {{CardFlag}}, which is either empty, or in the format "flagN" where N is 1-4</li>
          <li>Fix bulk flag changes in Browse screen not syncing</li>
          <li>Fix advanced menu in editor not showing shortcut keys</li>
          <li>When UI fails to load after resuming computer from sync, show a tooltip and automatically refresh</li>
          <li>Clean up old mplayer instances after a crash so that profile renaming works</li>
          <li>Fix add-on list not refreshing when toggling enabled in latest toolkit</li>
          <li>Fix cursor jumping on first click in "Edit Current" area on Windows</li>
          <li>Preserve whitespace when pasting plain text</li>
          <li>Prevent errors caused by a timer firing after collection is unloaded</li>
          <li>Ensure a full sync is forced when restoring from a backup</li>
          <li>Ensure full window is on screen when displaying windows on a changed screen layout</li>
          <li>Improvements to the add-ons, debug console, and error screens (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Ensure {{Deck}} shows the correct deck when adding (thanks to Arthur)</li>
          <li>Ensure windows don’t get shown off-screen</li>
          <li>Remember add-on window size and position</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-01-02" version="2.1.8"/>
    <release date="2018-12-17" version="2.1.7"/>
    <release date="2018-12-10" version="2.1.6"/>
    <release date="2018-10-01" version="2.1.5"/>
    <release date="2018-09-05" version="2.1.4"/>
    <release date="2018-03-01" version="2.1.0beta37"/>
    <release date="2018-02-05" version="2.1.0beta36"/>
  </releases>
  <provides>
    <id>net.ankiweb.Anki.desktop</id>
  </provides>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">anki.desktop</launchable>
  <update_contact>dan_at_reactivated.net</update_contact>
</component>
