<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.ankiweb.Anki</id>
  <translation type="gettext">anki</translation>
  <name>Anki</name>
  <summary>Powerful, intelligent flash cards</summary>
  <developer_name>Damien Elmes</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>Anki is a program which makes remembering things easy. Because it's a lot more efficient than traditional study methods, you can either greatly decrease your time spent studying, or greatly increase the amount you learn.</p>
    <p>Anyone who needs to remember things in their daily life can benefit from Anki. Since it is content-agnostic and supports images, audio, videos and scientific markup (via LaTeX), the possibilities are endless.</p>
    <p>Optional LaTeX support is provided by the TeX Live Flatpak extension org.freedesktop.Sdk.Extension.texlive//21.08.</p>
  </description>
  <kudos>
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
    <kudo>UserDocs</kudo>
  </kudos>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <url type="homepage">https://apps.ankiweb.net/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://anki.tenderapp.com/discussions/ankidesktop</url>
  <url type="help">https://apps.ankiweb.net/docs/manual.html</url>
  <url type="donation">https://apps.ankiweb.net/support/</url>
  <url type="translate">https://apps.ankiweb.net/docs/manual.html#_app_translations</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image type="source">https://i.imgur.com/zauNqLH.png</image>
      <caption>Flashcard and answer</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release date="2022-04-09" version="2.1.50">
      <description>
        <p><b>Platform-Specific Changes (Linux)</b></p>
        <ul>
          <li>The Linux builds need zstd to decompress.</li>
          <li>The packaged version requires glibc 2.27 or later.</li>
          <li>A wheel is now provided for ARM64 Linux, and requires glibc 2.31 or greater.</li>
          <li>Both Fcitx4 and Fcitx5 support is now bundled.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>Qt6</b></p>
        <p>The packaged builds now come in separate Qt5 and Qt6 versions. Each version has some advantages and disadvantages. The Flatpak build will use Qt5 for now.</p>
        <p><b>Scheduler Changes</b></p>
        <p>The V1 scheduler is no longer supported. If you have not yet updated to V2 or V3, you will be prompted to update when you attempt to review cards in 2.1.50.</p>
        <p>This release includes a number of improvements to the V3 scheduler, mostly thanks to Rumo:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Intermediate deck limits now affect their children. Please see the scheduler page for more info.</li>
          <li>When new cards are answered, Anki now records their original position. When you later export a shared deck without scheduling, the original positions will be restored.</li>
          <li>The Forget action now gives you options to restore the original card position, and to reset the card's lapse and repetition counters.</li>
          <li>The gathering and sorting of new cards has been reworked, trading a little performance for more intuitive behaviour:
            <ul>
              <li>It is now possible to sort notes or cards randomly at gather time, ensuring a random selection is taken from all available new cards.</li>
              <li>The gather order and sort order options have been simplified, but should offer the same functionality as before. Please check your deck options after upgrading, as some users may need to adjust their display order settings to match what they were using before.</li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>The overview screen now shows how many cards will be buried.</li>
          <li>Added a separate option to control burying of interday learning siblings.</li>
          <li>Fixed interday learning siblings not being buried during review, causing them to reappear later after actions like an edit.</li>
          <li>If you have more than 2 learning steps, after the first step, Hard repeats the previous delay, instead of being the average of the previous and next step.</li>
          <li>When a Hard learning step exceeds a day, it is now rounded to a full day, so the delay does not vary depending on the time of day you answer.</li>
          <li>Fuzz is applied more evenly now, especially with smaller intervals.</li>
          <li>Fixed new cards not decrementing the review limit, which could lead to more new cards appearing after the review limit was reached.</li>
          <li>Review cards and new cards are now interspersed more evenly.</li>
          <li>When using Custom Study to extend deck limits in the V3 scheduler, parent/child limits of the selected deck are no longer adjusted.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>Editor Changes</b></p>
        <p>Most of these changes are thanks to Henrik.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>A redesigned editing area, and a redesigned tag editor.</li>
          <li>MathJax has a live preview.</li>
          <li>HTML source and rendered text can be viewed at the same time.</li>
          <li>The HTML editor now matches the current Anki theme.</li>
          <li>Images can be resized within the editor.</li>
          <li>Fields can now have an optional description/tooltip assigned to them (thanks to Matthias, Henrik &amp; Rumo).</li>
          <li>The "remove formatting" button now offers a choice of what to remove.</li>
          <li>Adjust color picker shortcut, and apply color when different color selected.</li>
          <li>Reduced editor button size on Windows/Linux (thanks to Matthias).</li>
          <li>Fixed IME input after pressing tab.</li>
          <li>Fixed media files not being inserted at cursor position on Windows.</li>
          <li>Cloze shortcut correctly positions cursor.</li>
          <li>Added a separate cloze button to repeat the current cloze.</li>
          <li>Lots of behind-the-scenes changes and fixes. Because of the extensive changes, some add-ons that modify the editing screen will have broken.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>New Features</b></p>
        <ul>
          <li>Anki will now switch to day or night mode automatically depending on your system settings. You can force day or night mode in the Preferences screen. (thanks in large part to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Reworked backup handling (mostly thanks to Rumo):
            <ul>
              <li>Backups are created much faster than they were previously.</li>
              <li>Anki can now create backups periodically. The default is every 30 minutes; you can adjust this in the preferences screen.</li>
              <li>There are new options in the preferences to control the number of daily, weekly and monthly backups you'd like to retain.</li>
              <li>The File menu now has an option to create a backup immediately.</li>
              <li>Because the backup storage format has changed, backups created with 2.1.50 will not be importable into older Anki versions.</li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>Reworked .colpkg import/export (thanks to Rumo):
            <ul>
              <li>When exporting, you can optionally target Anki 2.1.50+. When doing so, imports and exports are faster, and media files will be compressed, but the resulting .colpkg will not be readable by older Anki clients.</li>
              <li>Collections are now checked for corruption when importing.</li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>An option to ignore accents in searches by default has been added to preferences screen (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>The Card Info screen now updates automatically as you change to a different card (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Added a View menu to the main window and browse window (thanks to Rumo). The view menu provides options to zoom in and out, and to toggle a full screen mode. Due to technical issues, the full screen mode is not currently available on Windows when graphics acceleration is enabled.</li>
          <li>A new TTS tag format that allows you to combine extra text and multiple fields, such as [anki:tts lang=en_US]Here is {{Field1}} and {{Field2}}[/anki:tts] (thanks to Rumo). There are no plans to deprecate the old TTS syntax - either can be used.</li>
          <li>Added an option to add/remove sidebar tag to selected notes (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Be smarter about mapping existing text to new fields when switching notetypes in the Add screen (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Apkg files can now be dragged on the main window to import them (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Added a "Create Copy" option in the browse screen and review screen, to copy selected note's contents into the Add window (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>You can now search for tags by regular expression (thanks to Rumo). One use for this is locating notes that are tagged with a parent tag, while not matching ones tagged with parent::child: tag:re:^parent$.</li>
          <li>When switching Anki versions, an add-on update check is run on startup (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Make links with target=_blank work (thanks to Danish).</li>
          <li>Added "Forget Card" action to review screen (thanks to Araceli).</li>
          <li>Added Belarusian and Odia to available languages in the preferences.</li>
          <li>Added a silent option (/s) for the Windows uninstaller (thanks to Patric).</li>
          <li>Added tooltips to some browser columns (thanks to Rumo).</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>Other Improvements</b></p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a "Learn" label to the learning counts in the deck list.</li>
          <li>Added shortcut keys for creating lists and indentation (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Allow longer maximum answer times in the deck settings (thanks to Bruce).</li>
          <li>Behind-the-scenes improvements to the deck and notetype selectors (thanks to Sam).</li>
          <li>Change cards/notes toggle to Ctrl/Cmd+Alt+T to avoid conflict on macOS.</li>
          <li>Changed the "Previous Card Info" shortcut to avoid a conflict with language input.</li>
          <li>Colpkg imports now always require a full sync.</li>
          <li>Deck creation in the custom study screen has been reworked, and now supports undo properly (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Don't show error when gsettings exists but does not have a GNOME theme set (thanks to Spooghetti420).</li>
          <li>Don't show error when Windows color scheme setting is missing (thanks to qxo).</li>
          <li>Fall back on regular file deletion when no recycling bin/trash folder is available on Linux.</li>
          <li>Filtered decks in 'order added' now sort by card template.</li>
          <li>Fix deck name not updating after deck/notetype renamed (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed "tag duplicates" possibly operating on stale data (thanks to Ren).</li>
          <li>Fixed a number of issues with the preview window (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed AltGr triggering Ctrl+Alt shortcuts on Windows (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Fixed an error loading the old deck options screen when using Python 3.10.</li>
          <li>Fixed an error that could appear when clicking on the sidebar (thanks to qxo).</li>
          <li>Fixed an error that could occur in the browser when switching profiles (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed an error when an installed TTS voice on Windows supported multiple languages (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Fixed an error when exporting a collection with media files in it with very old modification dates (thanks to gnnoh).</li>
          <li>Fixed an intermittent error when building on Windows.</li>
          <li>Fixed error shown when double-tapping answer buttons on the v3 scheduler.</li>
          <li>Fixed errors and display issues when flagging and undoing in the review screen.</li>
          <li>Fixed external scripts being executed out of order (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed field content sometimes spilling outside container (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed flicker in review screen when referencing external js, and preload css files (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed incorrect card count in timebox after undo (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Fixed new card position appearing as a date when cards were in preview (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Fixed newly-added deck not being selected in the Add screen (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed quotation of "and" and "or" in search (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Fixed some parts of the media handling code matching more HTML tags than it should have (thanks to Brayan).</li>
          <li>Fixed sound failing to play after exporting a collection (thanks to Rumo and Kelciour).</li>
          <li>Fixed the deck list showing up blank in collections with many expanded decks.</li>
          <li>Fixed the main window sometimes failing to load properly when Anki starts (which could lead to blank windows, a giant sync icon, etc).</li>
          <li>Fixed unwanted &lt;div&gt; being left behind when deleting field contents (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed various memory leaks (thanks to Rumo and Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Flip sidebar location in RTL mode (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Hide "open new window" action in GNOME (thanks to Fusion future &amp; Felipe).</li>
          <li>Improve search highlight color in templates screen (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Improved display of the card info screen (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Improved localization of large numbers in the graphs, and various layout tweaks (thanks to Vova).</li>
          <li>Improved performance with large selections in the Browse screen (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Improvements to the Change Notetype screen (thanks to Matthias).</li>
          <li>Performance improvements for searching through many fields with a wildcard search (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Randomized card positions now start at 1, which avoids a corner case in filtered deck scheduling.</li>
          <li>Reduced flicker when opening browser in night mode (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Report correct count in timebox screen with v2 scheduler (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Rows with database inconsistencies in the browse screen now prompt you to use "check database" instead of saying they were deleted (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Some behind-the-scenes code improvements (thanks to Sam).</li>
          <li>Support autoplay in audio tags again (thanks to Andreas).</li>
          <li>Support Markdown inside HTML tags in config.md (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>The 'future due' graph no longer shows learning cards in a filtered deck as being due a long time ago.</li>
          <li>The note: and card: searches no longer do a substring match (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>The Add Cards screen will no longer allow accidental triggering of main window shortcuts when it is open on a Mac (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>The calendar graph uses consistent coloring as years are changed (thanks to Ryan).</li>
          <li>The custom study screen no longer (sometimes incorrectly) limits the amount you can extend the daily limits by.</li>
          <li>The top and bottom bars will no longer zoom in/out, but the main area and editors can be zoomed in and out (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Truncate deck names in the deck list if they are too long (thanks to Sachin).</li>
          <li>Tweaks to the sidebar icons (thanks to Henrik).</li>
          <li>Updated translations - thanks as always to all the translators.</li>
          <li>Use white menubar on Windows (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Various behind-the-scenes fixes (thanks to Arthur).</li>
          <li>Various improvements to right-to-left display (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>When Anki encounters an issue with a card template, it now provides a link to a help page with more information (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Numerous other fixes and contributions, thanks to Rumo, Henrik, Abdo, Matthias, Evandro, Arthur, Soren, BlueGreenMagick, Yoshi, Jakub, Gesa, blue-putty, stopendy, TheFeelTrain and zjosua.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2021-10-26" version="2.1.49">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed cards not being automatically unburied when v3 scheduler enabled.</li>
          <li>Fixed incorrect learning count in v3 scheduler when interday learning cards were queued (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Work around an AnkiDroid inconsistency causing deck config to be reset if options edited on AnkiDroid.</li>
          <li>Fixed a memory leak in the Preview screen (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue copying filenames from the Check Media screen (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Fixed deck changing when toggling sticky fields (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Fixed invalid default column in notes mode in the Browse screen (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>The bury command ignores suspended cards now (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Anki no longer migrates any files from the old ~/Documents/Anki and ~/Anki folders.</li>
          <li>Increased number of card templates shown in card templates screen dropdown (thanks to Evando).</li>
          <li>Added a new example Dockerfile (thanks to Jakub).</li>
          <li>Handle spaces in Linux install location (thanks to lolilo).</li>
          <li>Work around a PyQt error on Python 3.10.</li>
          <li>Other minor changes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2021-09-21" version="2.1.48">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add "Previous Card Info" action to review screen (thanks to Evandro).</li>
          <li>Fix flag names not updating on profile switch (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Hide "Rename with Parents" for top-level items (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>"Add Field" action now correctly handles multi-word font names.</li>
          <li>Fix newline being added when coloring text (thanks to Henrik).</li>
          <li>Fix incorrect system font when running Anki in some non-English languages.</li>
          <li>Fix learning count sometimes jumping to a large number in the v3 scheduler.</li>
          <li>Another fix for Reposition command not working on buried/suspended cards.</li>
          <li>Preserve focus when changing notetype in the Add screen.</li>
          <li>Wayland can now be optionally enabled with an env var in the packaged builds, but remains off by default due to a number of bugs.</li>
          <li>Fix an error message that could appear when deleting notes (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>The card templates screen no longer defaults to filling empty fields when opened from the Add screen (thanks to BlueGreenMagick).</li>
          <li>Miscellaneous other fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2021-08-29" version="2.1.47">
      <description>
        <p>Changes to the v3 scheduler:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Interday learning cards are included in the learning count again, instead of the review count.</li>
          <li>Interday learning cards are still affected by the review limit. Interday learning cards are fetched first, then reviews, and finally new cards.</li>
          <li>Filtered decks with rescheduling disabled now log reviews, so the reviews will appear in your graphs.</li>
          <li>Added an option to sort reviews by ascending/descending ease.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where an error message could appear after undoing/redoing a mix of reviews and other changes.</li>
          <li>Fixed custom scheduling not working.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Other changes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The "timebox finished" message is now shown on card answer, instead of after revealing the next card. This should also address an issue where the message popped up outside of review.</li>
          <li>Added shortcut for Forget in the Browse screen.</li>
          <li>Fixed an error being shown when there was no current deck.</li>
          <li>Fixed incorrect quoting in duplicate search (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Fixed deck options inverting the "replay question when showing answer" option.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with ampersands in the Add Cards history button (thanks to Arthur).</li>
          <li>Fixed handling of audio/video tags (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Fixed errors playing audio when computer was slow to respond (thanks to Kelciour).</li>
          <li>Fixed preferences screen not updating undo menu, and causing an error when subsequently reviewing a card in the v3 scheduler.</li>
          <li>Fixed case changes being ignored in tag rename.</li>
          <li>Fixed error shown when DB check run on corrupt collection.</li>
          <li>Fixed deck options prompt showing the default deck, instead of the correct one.</li>
          <li>Fixed reposition command ignoring suspended cards.</li>
          <li>Fixed answer button highlight on Windows (thanks to Henrik).</li>
          <li>Fixed calendar graph day labels showing incorrectly in some timezones.</li>
          <li>Improved validation of add-on package names (thanks to BlueGreenMagick for the report and initial fix).</li>
        </ul>
        <p>For add-on developers:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The Svelte components Anki exports should now work correctly in add-ons, provided they exclude Svelte when bundling.</li>
          <li>WithShortcut is now also available.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2021-08-04" version="2.1.46">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix duplicate text when pasting with Ctrl+Shift+V (thanks to Henrik).</li>
          <li>Remember last colors in editing window (thanks to Henrik).</li>
          <li>Show flag and mark icons in preview window (thanks to Hikaru).</li>
          <li>Center first match when searching in sidebar (thanks to Abdo).</li>
          <li>Added F9/Shift+F9 shortcuts for sticky fields, and increase opacity (thanks to Henrik).</li>
          <li>Fixed starting ease specified in deck options not being used by v3 scheduler.</li>
          <li>Fixed learning cutoff not updating during review, and some learning cards remaining at the end of review in the v3 scheduler.</li>
          <li>Fixed Change Notetype not mapping fields correctly when count differed.</li>
          <li>The congrats screen now updates periodically again.</li>
          <li>Fixed Redo menu item showing Undo action name.</li>
          <li>Fixed notetype selection in the import screen.</li>
          <li>Fixed error in overview/congrats screen when there is no current deck.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2021-05-12" version="2.1.44">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Search text is no longer automatically quoted/interspersed with ANDs.</li>
          <li>Fix two backslashes being treated as one in MathJax.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2021-02-07" version="2.1.40">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed backup not being made when choosing "Download" when syncing.</li>
          <li>Fixed a slowdown after importing.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-12-26" version="2.1.38">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Use a new approach for recording audio. If you encounter any issues, the old PyAudio driver can be selected in the Preferences screen. The old driver will likely be retired in the future, so please let us know if the default system does not work for you.</li>
          <li>All built-in Windows TTS voices should now be supported on recent Windows 10 releases (thanks to Ryan).</li>
          <li>Fix the Reposition tool in the Browse screen not following the sort order.</li>
          <li>Reduce the default fade time in the review screen.</li>
          <li>The ANGLE video driver can now be selected in the Preferences on Windows.</li>
          <li>Fix some instances of the sync indicator remaining on after sync (thanks to Rumo).</li>
          <li>Work around –text-fg appearing in fields.</li>
          <li>Fix link in about screen (thanks to Abdo).</li>
	  <li>Fix ‘1’ being shown instead of the correct number in some Russian translations.</li>
          <li>Fixed invisible characters when adding new card templates (thanks to Henrik).</li>
          <li>Fixed duplicate check getting confused by non-breaking spaces (thanks to abdo).</li>
          <li>Don’t throw error when computer hostname is invalid.</li>
	  <li>Other minor changes (thanks to Henrik &amp; k12sh)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-10-02" version="2.1.35">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix a bug in Anki 2.1.29+ that caused excessive memory and CPU usage on long-running operations that show a progress bar, such as importing.</li>
          <li>Roll back Mac and Windows builds to Qt 5.14 again, as there are still issues with 5.15.</li>
          <li>Fix display issue in graphs on alternate Mac build.</li>
          <li>Fix preview not updating on multiple selection (thanks to abdo).</li>
          <li>Fix old content appearing when flagging immediately after typing.</li>
          <li>Fix some handling of * in searches.</li>
          <li>Sidebar now correctly escapes some characters (thanks to abdo).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-09-24" version="2.1.34">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix a bug in Anki 2.1.28+ where a newly created deck config would default to an ease of 130%. When updating, Anki will automatically change any deck configs with an ease of 130% back to 250%, and change any cards using those deck configs with a low ease back to an ease of 250%. (cont.)</li>
          <li>(cont.) Users who updated from an older Anki version and did not add new deck configurations should not be affected. If you have deliberately set an initial ease of 130%, please change it to 131% or greater prior to upgrading, so that Anki leaves your settings alone. Thanks to Aleksa for discovering the issue.</li>
          <li>Update the standard builds to the latest GUI toolkit version. Please report any improvements or regressions you notice.</li>
          <li>Dropped audio plays automatically again (thanks to abdo).</li>
          <li>Revert to older sound playing behaviour to work around issues (thanks to kelciour).</li>
          <li>is:due now stops at now+learn ahead limit, instead of end of day.</li>
          <li>Various improvements/fixes, some thanks Aleksa &amp; Henrik.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-08-30" version="2.1.33">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Access More button in review screen with ‘m’ (thanks to ANH).</li>
          <li>Audio no longer plays when dropped/pasted (thanks to ANH).</li>
          <li>Fix bulk tag adding not adding tags if tag is a substring of an existing tag (thanks to Soren)</li>
          <li>Fix cards not being unburied if leaving Anki open and the first action of a new day is a sync.</li>
          <li>Fix drag&amp;drop into existing content (thanks to ANH).</li>
          <li>Fix error when add-ons tried to access note/template in card template screen.</li>
          <li>Fix next learn message in congrats screen.</li>
          <li>Fix nonbreaking spaces in filenames not being handled properly.</li>
          <li>Fix text in export file selector (thanks to ANH).</li>
          <li>Fix timeouts in full syncs and media syncs again.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-08-25" version="2.1.32">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Roll back a change in the previous update that could cause syncs to time out.</li>
          <li>Fix sign up link in login screen.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-08-23" version="2.1.31">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Show card counts in pie graph, and other minor graph tweaks.</li>
          <li>Fix sync error+lost review when undoing in v2 filtered deck with scheduling off.</li>
          <li>Fix crash when dragging &amp; dropping, thanks to ANH25.</li>
          <li>Fix ‘stale notetype’ error after sync+add.</li>
          <li>Close “edit current” when current card deleted.</li>
          <li>Code improvements thanks to ANH, Arthur, Evandro, Henrik and Thomas.</li>
          <li>Find&amp;Replace completion is now case sensitive.</li>
          <li>Fix crash when recovering notes with missing notetype.</li>
          <li>Fix duplicate detection when input text is not normalized.</li>
          <li>Fix Empty Cards not ignoring BR tags.</li>
          <li>Fix Find&amp;Replace window sizing.</li>
          <li>Fix handling of nested legacy template directives.</li>
          <li>Fix issues with bulk tag removal.</li>
          <li>Fix mpv failing to play audio after it’s restarted, thanks to Kelciour.</li>
          <li>Fix some (rare) crashes.</li>
          <li>Full syncs and media syncs now terminate more quickly when the connection breaks.</li>
          <li>Improve support for getting proxies from Windows registry.</li>
          <li>Remove embedded direction markers in RTL cloze deletions.</li>
          <li>Strip nul characters from tags.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2020-08-09" version="2.1.30">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix move into/out of filtered decks not syncing.</li>
          <li>Add right axis to graphs.</li>
          <li>Add night mode and mobile class toggles in card layout screen (thanks to ANH25).</li>
          <li>Card counts graph now always shows table.</li>
          <li>Catch negative review times in DB check.</li>
          <li>Code improvements (thanks to Matt, phwoo, Evandro and aplaice).</li>
          <li>Fix a crash in the DB check when a note type was missing.</li>
          <li>Fix automatic logout not working when auth failure occurs.</li>
          <li>Fix deck list and graphs not including v2 scheduler cards with rescheduling disabled.</li>
          <li>Fix early reviews not appearing in review graph.</li>
          <li>Fix hour graph problem in timezones west of UTC.</li>
          <li>Fix negated conditonals being non-negated when renamed.</li>
          <li>Fix some syncing errors that could happen until Check Database was run.</li>
          <li>Fix some young cards being shown as mature in reviews graph.</li>
          <li>Handle multiple same-numbered clozes in cloze-only filter.</li>
          <li>Refresh tag list after clearing empty tags.</li>
          <li>Other minor fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-08-22" version="2.1.15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>The V2 scheduler now fully randomizes review cards due on a given day.</li>
          <li>Fix add-ons errors on Windows when profile path was short.</li>
          <li>Fix flag changes in Browse screen not syncing.</li>
          <li>Cleanup recording wav file when recording canceled.</li>
          <li>Fix the window icon on Wayland (thanks to Wilco).</li>
          <li>Add a progress bar to media deletion.</li>
          <li>Other minor changes.</li>
          <li>Fix a bug in the V2 scheduler that would cause partially learnt cards removed from filtered decks to revert to an earlier state.</li>
          <li>Fix a bug in the handling of relearning cards when switching back to the V1 scheduler.</li>
          <li>Fix lost space when pasting indented text.</li>
          <li>Limit image height relative to window height, not document height.</li>
          <li>Fix deck list being re-rendered unnecessarily.</li>
          <li>Remove the unable to connect to local port message.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-05-20" version="2.1.13">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix some issues that cause the main window to get stuck</li>
          <li>Fix an empty deck list sometimes appearing when restoring from a backup</li>
          <li>Fix Anki hanging after an error occurs during startup</li>
          <li>Fix error message when syncing with an unconfirmed email address</li>
          <li>Use jsonschema for add-on manifests (thanks to Erez)</li>
          <li>Warn in DB check when high due numbers are encountered</li>
          <li>Improve error messages on full disk and failed add-on deletion</li>
          <li>Fix relearning cards being given learning step count in V2 scheduler</li>
          <li>Fix preview window failing to appear when show both sides enabled</li>
          <li>Removing trailing BR tag when pasting into an empty field</li>
          <li>Don’t throw an error when non-Latin text in the Javascript console can’t be shown</li>
          <li>Double click on add-ons to edit their configuration (thanks to lovac42)</li>
          <li>Fix the window icon in a few screens (thanks to John)</li>
          <li>Improve the default type in the answer note type</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-04-23" version="2.1.12">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix fields appearing under editor buttons</li>
          <li>Fix memory leak in card layout screen</li>
          <li>Fix some issues with previewing in the Browse screen</li>
          <li>Fix card counts not updating when a review is undone</li>
          <li>Fix an error caused by missing note types</li>
          <li>Fix an issue checking for add-on updates (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Disable add-on config button when not appropriate (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Tweaks to the deck age graph binning (thanks to Jian)</li>
          <li>Add-ons hosted on AnkiWeb can now define conflicts in the manifest file</li>
          <li>Make sure mpv doesn’t attempt to load scripts from default location</li>
          <li>Other minor fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-03-11" version="2.1.11">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Change Undo shortcut back to Ctrl+Alt+Z/Cmd+Opt+Z in Browse screen, to prevent accidentally undoing non-text changes when editing fields</li>
          <li>Revert a previous card template optimization that could cause an error</li>
          <li>Suppress a spurious error message that could occur when editing</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-03-07" version="2.1.10">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add option to strip html in export</li>
          <li>Avoid nbsp for single spaces when pasting text</li>
          <li>Fix preview screen flashing when moving between cards</li>
          <li>Improvements to the add-ons screen (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Support .ankiaddon bundles (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Improve subpixel antialiasing on some machines (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Fix inability to start if problem occurs on first run</li>
          <li>Allow decreasing daily limits in custom study</li>
          <li>Add a button to copy debug info to about screen (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Allow add-ons to serve files from mediasrv (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>More user-friendly error messages for some network errors</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-02-20" version="2.1.9">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Update standard build to latest toolkit version</li>
          <li>Hardware acceleration defaults to off again on Windows/Linux, due to the issues it was causing some users. If you were not experiencing any issues, turning hardware acceleration back on in the preferences screen is recommended</li>
          <li>Various statistics fixes for the V2 scheduler, including an automatic remapping of button 2/3 in the review history when moving back and forth between scheduler versions so the "answer buttons" graph displays correctly</li>
          <li>Fix BR tags being included in empty fields (thanks to David and zjosua)</li>
          <li>Optimize card template repositioning (thanks to Arthur)</li>
          <li>Fix a crash when copying/cutting with an empty selection (thanks to David)</li>
          <li>Avoid screen flash when undoing reviews</li>
          <li>Make sure info/warning dialogs appear on top</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with just-typed text not being saved when using the mouse to save/add a card</li>
          <li>Added support for {{CardFlag}}, which is either empty, or in the format "flagN" where N is 1-4</li>
          <li>Fix bulk flag changes in Browse screen not syncing</li>
          <li>Fix advanced menu in editor not showing shortcut keys</li>
          <li>When UI fails to load after resuming computer from sync, show a tooltip and automatically refresh</li>
          <li>Clean up old mplayer instances after a crash so that profile renaming works</li>
          <li>Fix add-on list not refreshing when toggling enabled in latest toolkit</li>
          <li>Fix cursor jumping on first click in "Edit Current" area on Windows</li>
          <li>Preserve whitespace when pasting plain text</li>
          <li>Prevent errors caused by a timer firing after collection is unloaded</li>
          <li>Ensure a full sync is forced when restoring from a backup</li>
          <li>Ensure full window is on screen when displaying windows on a changed screen layout</li>
          <li>Improvements to the add-ons, debug console, and error screens (thanks to Glutanimate)</li>
          <li>Ensure {{Deck}} shows the correct deck when adding (thanks to Arthur)</li>
          <li>Ensure windows don’t get shown off-screen</li>
          <li>Remember add-on window size and position</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-01-02" version="2.1.8"/>
    <release date="2018-12-17" version="2.1.7"/>
    <release date="2018-12-10" version="2.1.6"/>
    <release date="2018-10-01" version="2.1.5"/>
    <release date="2018-09-05" version="2.1.4"/>
    <release date="2018-03-01" version="2.1.0beta37"/>
    <release date="2018-02-05" version="2.1.0beta36"/>
  </releases>
  <provides>
    <id>net.ankiweb.Anki.desktop</id>
  </provides>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">anki.desktop</launchable>
  <update_contact>dan_at_reactivated.net</update_contact>
</component>
